Frances A. Olawski Collection of Boott Mills Photographs 6642 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Frances A. Olawski Collection of Boott Mills Photographs
1942-1944
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Frances A. Olawski
Boott Mills
6642 P
1 folders
1 file folder
Gelatin silver prints, photographs.
Includes photographs, personal snapshots, of both male and female workers at the Boott Mills (Lowell, Mass.).
10065286
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, October 12, 2017
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, November 15, 2017
Biographical / Historical
The Boott Mills in Lowell, Massachusetts were a part of an extensive group of cotton mills, built in 1835 alongside a power canal system in this important cotton town. Their founder was Kirk Boott, one of the early mill leaders in Lowell.
Scope and Contents
Personal snapshots, mostly featuring Ruth (Monroe) Budd,; Olive (Dunn) Cairney, and Veronica (Murphy) Tasca, three deaf or hearing-impaired women working at Boott Mills.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Deaf; Women employees; Male employees; Management; Textile workers; Women textile workers; Lowell (Mass.); Boott Mills (Lowell, Mass.)
10065286
- Personal snapshots, 1942-1944 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Female workers at Boott Mills, 1942; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Gelatin silver print snapshot. Image depicts four women who were workers at the Boott Mills in Lowell, Mass. Left to right are: Ruth (Monroe) Budd of Lawrence, Mass.; Olive (Dunn) Cairney of West Newbury, Mass.; Veronica (Murphy) Tasca of Lawrence, Mass.; and Helen (last name unknown). Photo take outside in front of ivy-colored building; women wear dresses and jackets or light coats and carry brown paper lunch bags. Ruth, Olive, and Veronica were hearing impaired or deaf. See other photos in this series (items 2, 3, 6, and 8) for other views of these workers. 11 x 8.25 cm.
    Format: black and white photograph.
  - Item 2: Female Boott Mils workers relaxing, 1942; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print snapshot. Image depicts three women who were workers at the Boott Mills in Lowell, Mass. Left to right are: Irene (Marchand) Allegra of Lowell, Mass.; Veronica (Murphy) Tasca of Lawrence, Mass.; and Olive (Dunn) Cairney of West Newbury, Mass. Photo taken at the Lowell Y.W.C.A. Irene holds a soda bottle; Olive has a brown paper lunch bag in her lap. All three women were hearing impaired or deaf. See other photos in this series (items 1, 3, 6, and 8) for other views of these workers. 12.5 x 9 cm.
  - Item 3: Female Boott Mils workers relaxing, 1942; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print snapshot. Image depicts three women who were workers at the Boott Mills in Lowell, Mass. Left to right are: Ruth (Monroe) Budd of Lawrence, Mass.; Veronica (Murphy) Tasca of Lawrence, Mass.; and Olive (Dunn) Cairney of West Newbury, Mass. Photo taken at the Lowell Y.W.C.A. Ruth holds a glass in her right hand. All three women were hearing impaired or deaf. See other photos in this series (items 1, 2, 6, and 8) for other views of these workers. 12.5 x 9 cm.
  - Item 4: Helen & Eddie, 1944; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print snapshot. Image depicts a man and a woman standing outside a house; both wear winter overcoats; the man wears a hat and the woman has a corsage pinned to her coat. Identified only as "Helen & Eddie" on the reverse of the photograph; one or both apparently worked at the Boott Mills in Lowell, Mass. 8.25 x 10.5 cm.
  - Item 5: Mr. Camara, 1942; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print snapshot. Image depicts a man in a full business suit, wearing a hat, posed outside on the street (cars parked on the street behind him). Identified on the front of the photo as "Our Boss Mr. Camara" and on the back as "Boott Mill, Lowell, Mass., July 8." 6.5 x 9.25 cm.
  - Item 6: Boott Mills workers eating lunch, 1942; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print snapshot. Image depicts three women who were workers at the Boott Mills in Lowell, Mass., eating lunch, July 8. Left to right are: Olive (Dunn) Cairney of West Newbury, Mass.; Irene (Marchand) Allegra of Lowell, Mass.; and Veronica (Murphy) Tasca of Lawrence, Mass. Photo taken outside; the three women wear aprons to protect their dresses. All three women were hearing impaired or deaf. See other photos in this series (items 1, 2, 3, and 8) for other views of these workers. 6.5 x 9.25 cm.
  - Item 7: Arthur T. St. Onge, 1942; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print snapshot. Image depicts man dressed in work shirt and pants, posed outside (the Boott Mills clock tower is visible in the background); photo labeled on the front: "Here's Our Pal Arthur T. St. Onge," and on the reverse: "Boott Mills, Lowell, Mass., July 8, 168 Charles St., Lowell, Mass." The 1942 Lowell city directory lists St. Onge as an operative at the Boott, residing at 168 Charles St. 6.5 x 9.25 cm.
  - Item 8: Boott Mills workers eating lunch, 1942; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print snapshot. Image depicts three women who were workers at the Boott Mills in Lowell, Mass., eating lunch, July 8. Left to right are: Ruth (Monroe) Budd of Lawrence, Mass.; Irene (Marchand) Allegra of Lowell, Mass.; and Veronica (Murphy) Tasca of Lawrence, Mass. Photo taken outside; the three women wear aprons to protect their dresses. All three women were hearing impaired or deaf. See other photos in this series (items 1, 2, 3, and 6) for other views of these workers. 6.5 x 9.25 cm.
  - Item 9: Loomfixers, 1942; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print snapshot. Image depicts group of men posed outside (the Boott Mills clocktower visible in the background), July 8. Identified on the front as "Our Gang Loomfixers" and on the reverse as (clockwise? Arthur St. Onge is kneeling in front - see item 7): "Big Art - Arthur Pasquille [sp?], Cotie - Albert Cote, Lucien Milletta, Aimie, Arthur, Little Art - Arthur St. Onge. Boott Mills, July 8, Lowell, Mass." 6.5 x 9.25 cm.